University of Connecticut, University Communications Office Records 1995.0007
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, University Communications Office Records
1966-2009
1995.0007
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
30.15 Linear feet
The office of University Communications is responsible for strategic marketing and planning to promote the University's image and enhance its reputation among key local, regional and national audiences. Supporting this endeavor on the Storrs campus are seven units: Design Services, Internet Services, Lodewick Visitors Center, Marketing Services, Multimedia Services, University Events, and University News and Information. The communications office is also the primary source for news and information about the university, and has helped to educate the public about university life and academics. The mission of University Communications is to serve as a primary source of UConn news and information and to promote strategically the University as a national leader in higher education, research, and service.They accomplish this by: Collaborating with the University’s schools and colleges, departments, and regional campuses to create effective communications; Creating marketing and communications initiatives that raise awareness of the University’s excellence and accomplishments; Fostering professional relationships with external news organizations to ensure accurate and timely reporting of University stories; Supporting outreach to key audiences through events that engage the University’s many constituencies and build goodwill for UConn; Providing visitors with a comprehensive introduction to the University community through illustrative exhibits and dynamic campus tours. Throughout the University of Connecticut's history, the communications office has been known as the College Editor, University Relations, the Sports Information Office, and the Office of Public Information. The collection houses communication records from 1979 to present.
History
The University Communications Office has a long and varied history beginning with the University Editorial Office which opened in 1922 under the direction of Walter Stemmons, College Editor. In 1954, after Mr. Stemmons retired, the office was renamed to reflect its broadened responsibilities. The Division of Communication, directed by John H. Gleason, had four subdivisions: General News (News Office), Sports Information, University Photography (Photo Lab), and Publications-Central Duplicating. In 1962, Donald Friedman became head of the office. In 1964, the name was again changed, this time to Office of Public Information and Publications. This office absorbed University News, Sports Information, Photography, Publications, and Central Duplicating. In 1967, Raymond J. Buck became Director of University Publications when the Office became the Office of Public Information (OPI). Friedman continued to work for Buck as director of OPI until 1977 when Walter S. McGowen became the director. Sports Information was transferred to the Division of Athletics in 1977/1978.
In 1986, the office was renamed the Office of University Relations and Karen Grava Williams was named Director of Institutional Relations. The following year, the office was divided into two offices: Institutional Relations and University Publications.
Although the responsibilities of the unit have remained the same, by 2005 was known as University Communications.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection contains Administrative Records, Correspondence, Notes, Publications, Media Contacts, Student and Faculty Activity, Biographies, Departmental Communications, News Releases, Campus-wide Communications as published in the UConn Chronicle, UConn Advance, Announce-L, and, Daily Digest, from 1979 to present.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records were donated to the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
University of Connecticut.; Administrative records; Archives (institutions); Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence; Notes; Photographs; Publications
- Series I: Inventory, 1966-2004
  - Correspondence, Administrative Records, 2001-2004; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 4)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Study Abroad (program information, student applications, general correspondence, student rosters, orientation feedback, evaluation forms)]
  - Administrative Records, Brochures, News Releases, Notes, 1983-1993; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 5)
    [Subjects include: University Relations News Releases, academic study plans, newsletters, handwritten notes, newspaper article, newspaper clippings, photocopies of newspaper articles, surveys, Affirmative Action Plan (1992&1993), academic affairs and provost, academic advisory center, center for academic programs, academic plan, academic societies, accounting department, actuarial science, accredation, center for actuarial studies, admissions, advance survey, advanced degrees, advance technology center for precision manufacturing, affirmative action office, affirmative action program, activity of students-african american cultural center, institute for african american studies, agriculture business, cornucopia, agricultural annual report]
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Newspapers, 1971-1993; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 6)
    [Subjects include: atrium gallery news releases, back to school newpaper articles, handwritten notes, athletic pprograms information, newspapers and newspaper clippings about UConn athletics, a taste of Storrs restaurants, associated student commissaries, Asian-American issues, annual fund, Arab cultural center, Armenian studies program, Archaeology, Anthropology, Animal Science Department, American English Language Institute, AAUP, Alumni Magazine, Alpha Pi Omega]
  - Newspapers, Administrative Records, Clippings, 1968-1997; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 7)
    [Subjects include: Auditors, Alpha Lambda Delta, Alpha Eta (School of Allied Health Professionals, Agriculture & Natural Resources, CANR Clips, Alcohol Education, Alcohol Policy Review Committee, Allied Health Professions School, Black History Month 1984, Black History Month 1974-1983, B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation, BIGALA of Uconn, Biological Sciences Group, Biobehavioral Science, Beta Gamma Sigma (Honary Business Society), B.E.S.T. Program, Best North America, Benton Biography, Benton Museum of Art 1990 Tiffany Lamps]
  - Photographs, Correspondence, Newspaper, Clippings, Notes, 1967-1997; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 8)
    [Subjects include: Bloodmobile, Board of Regents, Booth Research Center, Board of Trustees, Bookmobile, Branford House, Budget, School of Business Administration, Business Environment and Policy Department (Board of Advisors), Campus Appearance Committee, Campus Crime, Campus Plan, Sea Grant, Career Service and Cooperative Education Department, Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, Carnegie Bank, Castleman, Catalogs Pamphlets]
  - Notes, Correspondence, Clippings, 1968-2000; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: computer center, computer appl. & research center, Communication Science, Committee for a Greater Umiversity, Community Services, Committee for a Greater University, Committee Against Racism, Comentary Writing Workshop Feb.8, 2000, Commencement Speakers' Adresses, College Guides, Bill Clinton at UConn, Class of '47 Gift, Cleaners, Civil Engineering, Citi, Christmas Tree Lighting, Chinese Student Association, Chip/Cochlear Implant, Child Development Lab, Chicken interfeem, Child Care Conference, Chemistry-CLAS, Chemical PITS, Chemical Engineering, Chancellor's Special Task Force on Community and Civility, Center for Marital and Family Therapy, Center for Real Estate and Urban Economic Studies-SBA, Centenial, Demonstrations]
  - Photographs, Clippings, Notes, 1968-1992; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 11)
    [Subjects include: Wallace Stevens Poetry Award Program, CovenantMutual Insurace Graduate Award, Julius B. Fleischmann Memorial Award, Spirer/Dueker Award, Robert C. Cleverdon Memorial Award, Mina M. Boxter Award, Covenant Mutual Insurace Company Fellowship Award, Connecticut Higher Education Community Service Award-1993, Connecticut Association of Real Estate Boards Award, Miscellaneous Awards (1974-1984)]
  - Photographs, Clippings, Notes, Administrative Records, 1985-1995; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 12)
    [Subjects include: Engineering School General-1989, Engineering-Eurotech, Engineering Fortune Magazine, CLAS-English (Connecticut Writing Project), English Dept., CLAS English, English 1990, Engineering Fact Sheets UTC Building, Endowment Fund, Computer Sceience & Electrical Engineering, Computer Center Account, Employee Achievement Awards, Emiliana Pasca Noether Chair in Modern Italian History, Education- Sports & Leisure School, Electrical Insulation Research Center, Education School Educational Research Bureau]
  - Notes, Administrative Records, Photographs, Clippings, 1985-1996; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 13)
    [Subjects include: Educational Properties Inc., College of Technology-Proposed, Minority Engineering Program, VCEP, Robotics, Engineering School General 1990, Extended and Continuing Education (Labor Education Center), Engineering Annual Open House, Engineering Precision Manufacturing, Engineering Newsletter, Executive MBA, Center for Study of Ethical Issues in War and Peace, Environmental Health and Safety Center, Enrollment Data, Environmental Engineering, Faculty, Facilities Office, Extended and Continuting Education (Labor Education Center), Robert L. Kanter Memorial Lecture, Extended and Continuing Education, Federal Credit Union of Student, Family Transitions, Family Studies School]
  - Administrative Records, Photographs, Correspondence, Clippings, 1966-1997; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 15)
    [Subjects include: Financial Tips, Fine Arts School-Dramatic Arts, Fine Arts School, Parents, Center for Study of Parental Acceptance & Rejection, Parenting Releases, Parents Weekend, Parent Day, Peace Corps Program, Pathobiology-Rabies, Pathobiology-CANR, Parking, Peace Games 1990, Pfizer-General, Pharmacy: Pfizer, Pharmacy: Hewitt Lecturship, Pesticides, Personnel Department, Pharmacy School, Phi Alpha Theta]
  - Clippings, Administrative Records, Photographs, Notes, 1968-1997; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 16)
    [Subjects include: Polo, Poultry, Poverty, Policies, Pi Lambda Theta, Physiology & Neurobiology, Philosophy-CLAS, Phi Kappa Phi, Phi Delta Kappa, Phi Beta Kappa]
- Series II: 2001 Transfer, 1995-1999
  - Correspondence, Notes, Publications, 1995 July - 1996 July (Box 1)
    [Subjects include: All media outlet contacts with The University of Connecticut as well as, relevance of the contact. Small record of specific events of media importance and attendance.]
  - Administrative Records, Correspondence, Notes, Publications, 1996 August - December, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: All media outlet contacts with The University of Connecticut as well as, relevance of the contact. Includes a small record of publications and administrative records concerning The University of Connecticut in the media. Record of published works from spring weekend 1998.]
  - Correspondence, Notes, 1995-1996; 1.3 Linear feet (Box 3)
    [Subjects include: media contacts, e-mails (arranged by month)]
- Series III: Landfill records
  The series contains publications, correspondence, reports and maps pertaining to the remediation and closure of the University's landfill and chemical pits from 1993 through 2009.
  - Draft supplemental hydrogeologic investigation scope of work, UConn Landfill, Storrs, Connecticut, 2000 January (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Scope of Study (Second draft) Hydrogeologic Investigation, UConn Landfill, 1998 December (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Wetland Mitigation monitoring report 2, 2009 (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Narrative accomplishment report, Cooperative Extension System, CANR, 1993-1994 (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Draft preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report, UConn Landfill, v. 8 (2 ff), 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Construction completion report, Landfill and former chemical pits area, v. III of III (3 ff), 2009 August (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Construction completion report, Landfill and former chemical pits area, v. I of III (2 ff), 2009 August (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Construction completion report, Landfill and former chemical pits area, v. II of III (3 ff), 2009 August (Box 2013.0031_1)
  - Correspondence, 1999 April 20 (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Addendum to Scope of Study Hydrogeologic investigation, UConn landfill, 1999 April (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Scope of study, Hydrogeologic investigation, UConn landfill, 1999 January (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Laboratory Quality Assurance plan for the hydrogeologic investigation of the University of Connecticut landfill, 1999 March 11 (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Appendix A, Appendix E, undated (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Report on Lot F landfill closure, 1999 April (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Technical specifications Lot F landfill closure, 1999 May (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Report on Lot F landfill closure, 1999 January (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Construction Summary, Landfill closure, Main Campus landfill, 1999 January (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 1999 April - June (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 1999 January - March (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 2001 April - June (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 2001 January - March (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 2000 April - June (Box 2013.0031_2)
  - Administrative file, 2000 January - March (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Administrative file, 2000 October - December (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Administrative file, 2000 July - September (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Draft Preliminary hydrogeologic Investigation report, v. 2 Tables (2 ff), 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Draft Preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report, v. 6 (3 ff), 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Integrated Surface-Geophysical investigation of the University of Connecticut Landfill, 2002 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Draft report Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. III of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Draft report Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. IV of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Draft report Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. VIII of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Integrated borehole-grophysical and hydraulic investigation of the fractured-rock aquifer near the University of Connecticut landfill, 2000-2001 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Hydraulic characterization of a fractured-rock aquifer using discrete-zone monitoring systems at the University of Connecticut landfill, 1999-2002 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Final site inspection, 1993 September 29 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Technical specifications for solid waste landfill closure (with map), 1998 July (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Correspondence and publications, 1998-1999 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Interim monitoring program, 1999 November (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Publications, 1999 (Box 2013.0031_3)
  - Final supplemental hydrogeologic investigation, scope of work (3 ff), 2000 May (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Final draft Preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report, 2002 February 29 (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Tables (draft), 2000 March (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Laboratory Quality Assurance plan for the hydrogeologic investigation of the University of Connecticut landfill, 2000 April 18 (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Public involvement surveys, undated (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Technical memorandaum former chemical pits test trenching program, 2001 April (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Technical memorandum study area conceptual model shallow groundwater, surface water, soil gas, soil and sediments, v. I of III--text, 2001 October (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Regina Villa Associates correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Study area conceptual model supplemental hydrogeologic investigation, v. II of III, tables, 2001 October (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Technical memorandum study area conceptual model shallow groundwater, surface water, soil gas, soil and sediments, v. III of III--figures and appendices, 2001 October (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Interim monitoring program report, 2001 February (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Draft Schematic water main expansion study, 2001 August (Box 2013.0031_4)
  - Scope of study, second draft, 1998 December (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Hydrogeologic study and related plans, initial submittal, 1998 July 23 (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Information regarding consent order, 1998 October - December (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Construction completion report, F lot disposal area (3 ff), 2006 January (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Hydrogeological study, revisions and responses to comments after 10/20 and 11/4 meetings, 1998 (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Final draft, preliminary hydrogeologic investigation, v. 1--text, 2000 February (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Draft preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report, v. I--text, 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Project manual, v. 1 of 4, Specifications, remedial action plan, 2005 August (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Addendum, Supplemental hydrogeologic investigation scope of work, 2000 July (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Draft report, comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Technological memorandum, ecological assessment, 2002 April (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Project manual--v. 4, Bidder's data package, remedial action plan, 2005 July (Box 2013.0031_5)
  - Correspondence, 2002 June 18 (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft report, Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. VI of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Integrated Surface-Geophysical investigation of the University of Connecticut Landfill, 2000 (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Borehole-Geophysical investigation of the University of Connecticut landfill, 2002 (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Technical memorandum, Bedrock groundwater conceptual model, 2002 April (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft report, comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. II of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft report, comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation report and remedial action plan, v. I of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Project manual, v. 2 of 4, use of CL&P right of way, remedial action plan, 2005 August (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Project manual, v. 3, summary of permits and related documents, 2005 July (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft final, Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan addendum, 2003 January (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Correspondence, 2003 January 16 (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Publication, 2003 January (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Technical memorandum, F lot conceptual model, 2002 January (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft report, comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, v. VII of VIII, 2002 October (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Technical memoranum, F lot conceptual model, v. I of II--text and tables, 2002 January (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft Preliminary Hydrogeologic investigation report (3 ff), v. 7, 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_6)
  - Draft preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report (3 ff), v. 5, 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Draft Preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report (3 ff), v. III-Figures, 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Draft Preliminary hydrogeologic investigation report (3 ff), v. 4, 1999 December (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, consent order, sediment documents, 2004 April 24 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, 2004 March 9 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Technical memorandum, supplemental remedial alternatives analysis, 2003 July (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Closure plan, 2003 August (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, Landfill wetlands permit, 2005 June 2 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Use of discrete-zone monitoring systems for hydraulic characterization of a fractured-rock aquifer at the University of Connecticut landfill, 1999-2002 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Borehole-geophysical and hydraulic investigation of the fractured-rock aquifer near the University of Connecticut landfill, 2000-2001 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Closure plan, 2004 January (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Publication, 2004 October (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, Closure plan, responses to comments, 2004 January 22 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Maps, Remedial action plan implementation, 2004 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, 2005 June 29 (Box 2013.0031_7)
  - Correspondence, 2004 July 22 (Box 2013.0031_8)
  - Comprehensive hydrogeologic investigation and remedial action plan, addendum No. 2, 2004 July (Box 2013.0031_8)